<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Blog</title>
    <link>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:08:06 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dude Where&#39;s My Output?</title>
      <link>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/dude-wheres-my-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 19:08:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/dude-wheres-my-output/</guid>
      <description>I recently had to build a simple project simulating a certificate authority, CRL distribution point, web server and client host. The web server ran Apache with a simple HTML page in conjunction with some PHP code. The purpose of the web server was to verify some messages signed by user x509 certificates that were, in turn, signed by the CA. The web server needed to display the output from some OpenSSL verification checks after getting the user x509, message signature and message file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Runtimes 2</title>
      <link>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/runtimes-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 03:53:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/runtimes-2/</guid>
      <description>Verbose if else v.s. one-liner if else This is a case that I believe to have seen actually impact runtimes somewhat consistently, so I&amp;rsquo;m interested to see if it was placebo or if this small change actually affects the runtime. The example goes as follows:
Case 1: Verbose def ifelse(x): if x: return True else: return False Case 2: One-liner def ifelse(x): return True if x else False We can see that given the same input x, we would get the same result in the return statement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Runtimes 1</title>
      <link>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/runtimes-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 04:51:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/runtimes-1/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of DSA questions In preparation for coding interviews I&amp;rsquo;ve been studying a lot of data structures and algorithms problems. The main goal when solving these problems is to work out a solution that has low time and space complexity. However when you submit questions on a online judge such as Leetcode, you tend to notice that some minor changes in your code, such as the order or way you write out if statements, can impact your runtime through the judge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelab 2</title>
      <link>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/homelab-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 21:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/homelab-2/</guid>
      <description>Hiatus It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since my last blog entry, but I had a draft of this post kicking around from October of 2021 talking about the stuff I did with the homelab (past tense, I&amp;rsquo;ll get to that). I can&amp;rsquo;t talk about the super technical details or challenges I faced since I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly remember what happened, but I will try my best.
Great things I had great aspirations for the homelab when I first got it running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homelab 1</title>
      <link>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/homelab-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 03:39:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/homelab-1/</guid>
      <description>Why, How and What I felt incredible joy after finishing my final exam of the term following 12 months of continuous schooling. But less than 72 hours later I was already bored. I needed something to do, so I made the Friedman translator. This was a project that would normally take me weeks due to dealing with school, but I finished it in under two days. I needed a bigger project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elliotte Friedman</title>
      <link>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/elliotte-friedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 21:13:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/elliotte-friedman/</guid>
      <description>Who is Elliotte Friedman? This is Elliotte Friedman.
 This tweet has since been deleted, here is a saved screenshot
 CAL and MON are not abbreviations. With this translator now you can make an educated guess as to what ELF is trying to say.
 What did Elliot Friedman say this time: Decipher  function friedman() { var acronym = document.getElementById(&#34;myText&#34;); var teams = [&#34;Anaheim Ducks&#34;, &#34;Arizona Coyotes&#34;, &#34;Boston Bruins&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Person AHK</title>
      <link>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/first-person-ahk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 19:34:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/first-person-ahk/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The first time I had ever used AHK was back in highschool. My friend made a Discord bot called &amp;ldquo;Starmine&amp;rdquo; that would give out points whenever a user typed !starmine.
It was a fun incremental/idle game that we all played, and while you could wait for the passive point generation, the fastest way to get points was to type !starmine.
The game got really competitive and as we went into the summer months and I needed a way to edge out the competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run a Tor relay as a student for free</title>
      <link>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/how-to-run-a-tor-relay-as-a-student-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 03:23:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://franklinliang.github.io/posts/how-to-run-a-tor-relay-as-a-student-for-free/</guid>
      <description>This post is based on Robert DeVore&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Run a Tor relay&amp;rdquo; found here: https://www.robertdevore.com/run-a-tor-relay/
 Tor is a service used by thousands of people everyday to access the internet safely and anonymously.
While I have been using Tor for quite some time, it always seemed daunting to help the Tor network by running a relay. Horror stories about getting mail from ISPs relating to the traffic of anonymous users accessing illegal materials masked by your IP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>